Guide to the Glenn Scarboro photographs, 1962-1976 RL.11522
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Glenn Scarboro photographs
1962-1976
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
Scarboro, Glenn, 1945-
RL.11522
1.5 Linear Feet 3 boxes 168 items
This collection of 166 black-and-white inkjet 13x19 inch photographs by Glenn Scarboro explores through street photography, landscapes, and portraits the social life and culture of southern Virginia in the 1960s and 1970s. About half of the photographs were taken in Danville, the photographer's hometown, while other images were taken in Richmond, Blacksburg, Roanoke, and other towns of the region. A dozen or so photographs were taken in other states such as Georgia and North Carolina, and there are a few from Rhode Island and New York. The street scenes in Danville and other towns include images of white and African American residents, small businesses, houses, and churches; rural themes include horse shows. county fairs, and country landscapes. There is also a series of family portraits taken in the 1960s. Collection includes one handmade photobook by Scarboro containing eleven photographs and handwritten text. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
168 items
Arrangement
Photographs are arranged and numbered in original order as received from the artist.
Biographical / Historical
Glenn Scarboro was born in January 1945 in Danville, Virginia, several months before the end of World War II. He learned to make photographs at age seventeen when a family friend who was a photographer for the local weekly newspaper asked him to cover an assignment for him.
Continuing his photography as he pursued a career in social work, Scarboro was particularly influenced by Emmet Gowin at the Fine Art Department at Richmond Professional Institute (now Virginia Commonwealth University), and by the work in Family of Man, edited by Edward Steichen, and The Decisive Moment by Henri Cartier-Bresson.
The Danville Museum of Fine Arts and History (DMFAH) has twice featured Scarboro's work in solo exhibitions: "The Views of Silent Space" in 2001, and in 2010, an exhibition titled "One Boy's Story: 35mm Street Photography and Other Ephemeral Moments." This work was later expanded to a collection of 166 photographs made from 1962 to 1976 and is the foundation of Scarboro's gift to the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research. Images may only be used for educational, non-commercial purposes; any other use requires the photographer's permission.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Glenn Scarboro photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The photographs were printed using an Epson Sure Color P800 printer with Epson Ultrachrome Ink on Epson Exhibition Fiber Base Paper from scanned 35mm and 6x6 negatives.
Scope and Contents
This collection of 166 13x19 inch black-and-white inkjet prints by Glenn Scarboro explores through street photography, landscapes, and portraits the social life and culture of southern Virginia in the 1960s and 1970s. About half of the photographs were taken in Danville, a small town with industries linked to tobacco, railroads, and textile mills, and the artist's hometown. Other images were taken in Richmond, Blacksburg, Roanoke, and other towns of the region. A dozen or so photographs were taken in other states such as Georgia and North Carolina, and there are a few from Rhode Island and New York.
The street scenes of Danville and other towns include images of white and African American residents of all ages and backgrounds, chiefly from the 1960s; small businesses; people and their cars; house exteriors and interiors; churches; and outdoor advertising and logos. One photograph is of the house of free black craftsman Thomas Day, in Milton, NC.
Rural themes include portraits of country people, barns and tobacco warehouses, livestock, and rural landscapes, with a large series of images particular focused on southern Virginia horse shows and county fairs.
There are no photographs of the social protests and political activities that took place in small towns such as Danville at that time, but the street photographs do speak to social culture and conditions in southern Virginia during the 1960s, and some, as the photographer notes, allude to the sense of social disruption and alienation in small-town Southern society.
The series ends with a series of portraits, chiefly of Scarboro and his immediate family, taken in the 1960s. One portrait of Scarboro in New York City was taken by photographer, instructor, and friend Emmet Gowin.
The collection also includes a 15-page handmade artist's book by Scarboro containing eleven black-and-white photographs taken in 1963 and printed from original negatives in 1965. The book was assembled in 1972 and is number six of a limited edition of seven, and features a unique cover with a pen-and-ink drawing.
A print inventory created by the photographer contains additional biographical narrative and commentary, and is available in the first box. The photographs are arranged in original order as received.
From the artist's statement: "There was a photograph in The Family of Man made by Jerry Cooke (originally published in Life magazine) of a woman sitting quite forlorn on a bench in a very dark place that gave no clues as to time, place, person or situation...which are the four psychiatric attributes of reality. She was alone. The quote under the photograph read, 'I am alone with the beating of my heart.' (Lui Chi) Making photographs in the streets of my hometown in the 60/70s calmed the beating of my unsettled heart and gave a face to the feelings of social alienation endemic to that time. Danville streets were the places of my earliest identity. In the process of becoming a close observer of ordinary life…I had become an artist.
Anxiety is always at the edge of identity."
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
African Americans -- Virginia; African Americans -- Virginia -- Social life and customs; City and town life -- Virginia -- Photographs; Country life -- Virginia -- Photographs; Documentary Photography -- Virginia -- Pittsylvania County; Fairs -- Virginia; Horse shows -- Virginia; Portrait photography -- United States; Danville (Va.) -- History; Danville (Va.) -- Photographs; Danville (Va.) -- Social conditions; Pittsylvania County (Va.) -- Photographs; Virginia -- Photographs; Virginia -- Social conditions; Virginia -- Social life and customs -- 20th century; Artists' books (books); Black-and-white photographs; Digital prints; Inkjet prints; Photobooks; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
- Street Photography and Other Ephemeral Moments, 1962-1976; 168 items 3 boxes 166 13x19 inch prints; 1 8 1/2 x 11 inch print; one handmade photobook
  Scope and Contents
  Body of documentary work by Glenn Scarboro, consisting of 166 13x19 inch black-and-white exhibit quality prints, and a handmade photobook, number 6 of 7 handmade books by Scarboro, with original photographs, ink sketches and handwritten text. Also includes a black-and-white photograph of the group of seven books by Scarboro.
  - White house, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0001)
  - Man at wall, downtown Danville, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0002)
  - Woman at market, downtown Danville, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0003)
  - Horse and cow, Rt. 460 West, near Blacksburg, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0004)
  - Three women, Roanoke, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0005)
  - Lady on corner of South Auburn Street, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0006)
  - Two women talking, Richmond, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0007)
  - Equus I at horse show, Orphanage Road, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0008)
  - Women in horse trailer, Orphanage Road, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0009)
  - Line of people in doubt, corner of Main and Union, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0010)
  - Ford and man, near Books, Strings, and Things, Blacksburg, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0011)
  - 1953 Chevrolet, Highway 58 East, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0012)
  - Young girl at Miller and Rhodes, Broad Street, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0013)
  - White horse in arena, Orphanage Road, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0014)
  - Building facades, downtown Richmond, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0015)
  - Pepsi logo, Richmond, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0016)
  - Family at revival, Indian Springs, GA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0017)
  - Three women on Main Street, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0018)
  - Horse show social, Orphanage Road, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0019)
  - Get Right with God, Highway 58 West, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0020)
  - Two women and Equus II, Orphanage Road, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0021)
  - Mother with child and friend, Rt. 460, near Blacksburg, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0022)
  - Family in a Ford truck, Rt. 460 West, near Blacksburg, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0023)
  - Cowboys, Virginia State Fair, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0024)
  - A Camellia cow, Virginia State Fair, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0025)
    A large cow statue advertising the Camellia Dairy.
  - Three barns, Buckingham County, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0026)
  - America, Airport Road, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0027)
  - American neighborhood, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0028)
  - Courtyard, Richmond, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0029)
  - Legs, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0030)
  - Corvair and kids, West Main Street, Danville, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0031)
  - A man studying art, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0032)
  - Five men, Broad Street, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0033)
  - Amusement ride, Virginia State Fair, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0034)
  - The flag, Roanoke, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0035)
  - Photo window, Blacksburg, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0036)
  - Tobacco warehouse, Highway 58 East, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0037)
  - Thomas Day house, Milton, NC, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0038)
  - Jehovah's witnesses, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0039)
  - Car hood, Highway 58 East, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0040)
  - Chevrolet Impala, Broad Street, Richmond, VA, 1974 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0041)
  - T.V. in Emmet's apartment, Providence, RI, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0042)
  - Lawrence, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Blacksburg, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0043)
  - Women's room, Virginia State Fair, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0044)
  - My sister Kathy, Danville, VA, 1962 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0045)
  - Bench, Blacksburg, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0046)
  - Chair, Milton, NC, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0047)
  - Jimmy's world, Buckingham County, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0048)
  - Child in background, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0049)
  - Young couple on Main Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0050)
  - Man in Cadillac, Patton Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0051)
  - Older couple on Main Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0052)
  - Young man at Johnson Drug Store, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0053)
  - Man at Haynesworth Camera Store, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0054)
  - Children playing, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0055)
  - Curb market, Spring Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0056)
  - Burlesque show at Danville Fair, Old Piney Forest Road, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0057)
  - Two women at Mr. Cue II, Union Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0058)
  - Woman at YMCA, Main Street, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0059)
  - Girl with glasses, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0060)
  - Newspaper boy, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0061)
  - School guard crossing, North Main Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0062)
  - Couple at F. W. Woolworth Company, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0063)
  - Woman at city armory wrestling match, Floyd Street, Danville, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0064)
  - Friday night wrestling at city armory, Floyd Street, Danville, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0065)
  - Sunday morning church services, Aiken Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0066)
  - Baby with mother, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0067)
  - Kid in rain suit, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0068)
  - Soldier with children, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0069)
  - Cowboy at horse show, Orphanage Road, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0070)
  - Bus stop at F. W. Woolworth Co., Union Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0071)
  - Friends at Danville Fair, Old Piney Forest Road, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0072)
  - Man with cane at horse show, Orphanage Road, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0073)
  - Man holding horse, Orphanage Road, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0074)
  - Lady among cars, Indian Springs GA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0075)
  - Two children, Industrial Avenue, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0076)
  - Horse with cars, Orphanage Road, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0077)
  - Billboard, Providence, RI, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0078)
  - Chevrolet truck, unknown location in Virginia, 1967 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0079)
  - Man in hat, Richmond, VA, 1969 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0080)
  - Mother and child, Richmond, VA, 1969 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0081)
  - Young girl, Virginia State Fair, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0082)
  - Goodman Furniture, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0083)
  - North Theater, North Main Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0084)
  - Sartorial elegance, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 1, Image RL.11522-P-0085)
  - Four men, location unknown in Virginia, circa 1963-1974 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0086)
  - Girls in Chevrolet Bel Air, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0087)
  - Randy with watermelons, Halifax County, VA, 1973 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0088)
  - Elmo's Barber Shop, Richmond, VA, 1969 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0089)
  - Mother and teapots, Danville, VA, 1973 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0090)
  - Two people in silence, Indian Springs, GA, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0091)
  - Women at horse show, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0092)
  - Three cows, Virginia State Fair, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0093)
  - Utility poles, Newport News, VA, 1969 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0094)
  - White horse, North Carolina, 1969 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0095)
  - Couple at horse show, Orphanage Road, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0096)
  - A moment of surprise, Broad Street, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0097)
  - Kids on corner, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0098)
  - Queen Nefertiti, Broad Street, Richmond, VA, 1969 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0099)
  - Man with cigarette, North Main Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0100)
  - Ballerina, Ann Boyer School of Dance, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0101)
  - Man at wrestling match, Floyd Street, Danville, VA, 1973 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0102)
  - Woman at Elk Club, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0103)
  - New York landscape, Millerton, NY, 1973 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0104)
  - Glenn Scarboro, Museum of Modern Art, New York, NY (photograph by Emmet Gowin), 1967 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0105)
  - Han's apartment, Richmond, VA, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0106)
  - Man at Elk Club, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0107)
  - Kid on horse, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0108)
  - Richmond Dairy, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0109)
  - Couple with camera, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0110)
  - Cathedral, Milton, NC, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0111)
  - Kids in store, Milton, NC, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0112)
  - Porters, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0113)
  - Couple in London Fog coats, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0114)
  - Line of people, Friday night wrestling, Danville, VA, 1973 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0115)
  - College students walking to downtown, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0116)
  - Older couple on corner, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0117)
  - Woman in store, Rt. 460 West, near Blacksburg, VA, 1967 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0118)
  - Girl in white socks, Main Street, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0119)
  - Tree in Reva's driveway, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0120)
  - High Street Baptist Church, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0121)
  - Man at horse trailers, Danville, VA, 1967 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0122)
  - Two kids playing, Richmond, VA, 1969 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0123)
  - Five kids on a porch, Richmond, VA, 1969 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0124)
  - Mother and child, Broad Street, Richmond, VA, 1969 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0125)
  - Two women under umbrella, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0126)
  - Spectators at burlesque show, Danville Fair, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0127)
  - Children in grocery store, North Main Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0128)
  - Houses, Roanoke, VA, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0129)
  - Perkins Barber Shop, Kemper Road, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0130)
  - A male gathering, Christiansburg, VA, 1967 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0131)
  - Kids with toy guns, Richmond, VA, 1969 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0132)
  - Drum major, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0133)
  - Car and house on Highway 58 East, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0134)
  - New American gothic, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0135)
  - Cadillac, Richmond, VA, 1972 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0136)
  - Two men talking, West Main Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0137)
  - Three men at bank, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0138)
  - American flag and young man, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0139)
  - Cub scouts as peppermint sticks, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0140)
  - Two women at Harnsbergers, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0141)
  - Man and woman at curb market, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0142)
  - Window and cup, Buckingham County, VA, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0143)
  - Father and two daughters at wedding, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0144)
  - Two painted trees on building, Richmond, VA, 1973 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0145)
  - Sexual politics, Indian Springs, GA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0146)
  - Bob's Grill, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0147)
  - Grocery shopping from back of a truck, Richmond, VA, 1969 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0148)
  - Man on porch, Danville, VA (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0149)
  - Uncle Squirrel and his cows, Nelson County, VA, 1973 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0150)
  - Young men playing basketball, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0151)
  - Man and two kids, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0152)
  - Fire station Number Three, Danville, VA, 1963 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0153)
  - Man and woman, Lower Main Street, Danville, VA, 1964 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0154)
  - Mother in hair curlers and smoking a cigarette, Danville, VA, 1962 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0155)
  - My sister in rain coat, Danville, VA, 1962 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0156)
  - My sister brushing hair, Danville, VA, 1962 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0157)
  - My sister with wild hair, Danville, VA, 1962 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0158)
  - My sister in Chair, Danville, VA, 1962 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0159)
  - My other sister drying hair and knitting, Danville, VA, 1962 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0160)
  - Kevin, Nelson County, VA, 1962 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0161)
  - A. J. Blankenship, Danville, VA, 1962 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0162)
  - Marilyn, Danville, VA, 1962 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0163)
  - Mother and Glenn, Danville, VA, 1973 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0164)
  - Jeff, Danville, VA, 1976 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0165)
  - Father and brother, Danville, VA, 1976 (Box 2, Image RL.11522-P-0166)
- Images: The Beginning and the End, 1963-1972; 15 pages 1 volume
  This spiral-bound handmade photobook, assembled by Scarboro in 1972, was prepared in a limited edition of seven, of which this is number six. It is centered around eleven 5x7 inch black-and-white gelatin silver photographs, dry-mounted back to back, taken in 1963 and developed in 1965 from original negatives. Titles were devised by the photographer in 2017. The images were taken in Virginia and North Carolina cities and towns and are a mix of streetscapes, still lifes, and portraits.
  The cover features a unique pen-and-ink drawing by the artist, followed by an introductory page with a handwritten image index of titles, places, and dates. Included in this series is a photograph of the group of seven unique photobooks, including the one in this collection.
  - Photograph of a group of seven handmade photobooks, after 1972 (Box 3, Image RL.11522-P-0167)
    Caption by library staff. The books were completed in 1972; the exact date of the photograph is unknown.
  - Images: the beginning and the end; a handmade book of photographs, 1963-1972 (Box 3, Volume RL.11522-P-0168)
    The eleven photographs featured were taken by Scarboro in 1963 and developed in 1965. The book was assembled in 1972. Titles devised by photographer in 2017. A few of the photographs are not in the main prints series.